<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Lisa DeBruine</title>
    <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://debruine.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://debruine.github.io/media/icon_hud41de7153c7fa400a999f8d222dc5c78_8091_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Simulation Workshops</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/datasim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/datasim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-simulation-for-factorial-designs&#34;&gt;Data simulation for factorial designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will cover the basics of simulation using {faux}. We will simulate data with factorial designs by specifying the within and between-subjects factor structure, each cell mean and standard deviation, and correlations between cells where appropriate. This can be used to create simulated data sets to be used in preparing the analysis code for pre-registrations or registered reports. We will also create data sets for simulation-based power analyses. Students will need to have very basic knowledge of R and R Markdown, and have installed {faux}, {afex} and {tidyverse}.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-simulation-for-mixed-designs&#34;&gt;Data simulation for mixed designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will cover simulating data for a mixed design, where trials are crossed with subjects. We will learn how to analyse this using {lme4}, with a focus on understanding how the simulation parameters correspond to the output. Finally, we will learn how to use simulation to calculate power. Students will need to have basic knowledge of R and R Markdown, some familiarity with mixed designs (even if they don’t currently analyse them with mixed models) and have installed {faux}, {afex}, {tidyverse}, and {lme4}.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Day Chart Challenge</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/30dcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/30dcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first year participating in the 30-day chart challenge. I&amp;rsquo;m making a book of tutorials for each chart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faux</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/faux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/faux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is useful to be able to simulate data with a specified structure. The faux package provides some functions to make this process easier for factorial designs and single- or multilevel data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Club</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/shiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to take your R coding skills to the next level in a fun atmosphere where we learn by doing? Join the Coding Club!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be starting from the very basics to use the shiny R package to create an interactive web app that can read from a Google Form and display tables and plots describing your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When: Every other Wednesday 14:00-15:00, starting 6 October 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;do-i-have-enough-experience&#34;&gt;Do I have enough experience?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you&amp;rsquo;re new to R coding; as long as you can open RStudio and load the shiny package, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to participate. All levels are welcome, including undergraduate students and staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;will-it-be-recorded&#34;&gt;Will it be recorded?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, if you&amp;rsquo;re staff or a student at the University of Glasgow, join the Methods &amp;amp; Metascience Team with the code j2z7m4w in Teams to access recordings on the Coding Club channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-computing-resources-do-i-need&#34;&gt;What computing resources do I need?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to have access to R and RStudio. We will use these packages to start: shiny, shinydashboard, tidyverse. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyteachr.github.io/reprores-v2/installingr.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instructions for installing on your own computer&lt;/a&gt; or use a university computer or &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.cloud/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RStudio Cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;i-have-more-questions&#34;&gt;I have more questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the Methods &amp;amp; MetaScience Team (it&amp;rsquo;s open to all at UofG) with the join code j2z7m4w in Teams and post questions in the Coding Club channel or email &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Lisa.DeBruine@glasgow.ac.uk&#34;&gt;Lisa.DeBruine@glasgow.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimentum</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/experimentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/experimentum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Experimentum is an open-source, online platform for psychology studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa DeBruine, Rebecca Lai, Benedict Jones, Rifah Abdullah, Gaby Mahrholz. (2020). Experimentum (Version v.0.2). Zenodo. doi:10.5281/zenodo.2634355&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Science Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/psa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/psa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The PSA is a globally distributed network of psychological science laboratories that coordinates data collection for democratically selected studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a founding member and was elected to a 3-year term as an Associate Director in 2021. I also was one of the lead researchers on the first project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psyTeachR</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/psyteachr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/psyteachr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The psyTeachR team at the University of Glasgow School of Psychology and Institute of Neuroscience and Psychology has successfully made the transition to teaching reproducible research using R across all undergraduate and postgraduate levels. Our curriculum now emphasizes essential ‘data science’ graduate skills that have been overlooked in traditional approaches to teaching, including programming skills, data visualisation, data wrangling and reproducible reports. Students learn about probability and inference through data simulation as well as by working with real datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebMorph</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/webmorph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/webmorph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of WebMorph and the associated R package, webmorphR, is to make the construction of image stimuli more reproducible, with a focus on face stimuli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;
webmorphR is now on CRAN!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This development of these tools was funded by ERC grant #647910 (KINSHIP).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
