<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Lisa DeBruine</title>
    <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://debruine.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://debruine.github.io/media/icon_hud41de7153c7fa400a999f8d222dc5c78_8091_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/glossary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of necessary jargon to learn for coding. The goal of glossary is to provide a lightweight solution for making glossaries in educational materials written in quarto or R Markdown. This package provides functions to link terms in text to their definitions in an external glossary file, as well as create a glossary table of all linked terms at the end of a section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully on CRAN soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to R Packages</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/coding-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/coding-club/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making an R package develops generic coding skills and gives you valuable insight to how R works. We’ll cover setting up a package project, creating functions, documenting them with roxygen, creating vignettes, unit testing, package testing, version control with git, and distribution with github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sessions ran Wednesdays from 16:05 to 17:00 UK time from October 5 to December 7, 2022 and recordings are linked to each chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
Register for free at [EventBrite](https://coding-club-packages.eventbrite.co.uk/) to help us keep organised and let us know a little bit about your experience. Space is unlimited, so don’t worry if you can’t make all of the dates. We’ll record the sessions and make them public ASAP so you can catch up if you miss the live session.
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Check</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/code-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/code-check/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project aims to make code review easier and more common in research. The first project is to create a guide for research code review aimed at novice to intermediate coders. We are also interested in creating resources for starting code check clubs. This group is open to anyone who wants to join, at any level of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🧠 &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cqrRDEYkhtZT9QRruZmUnPPN00VEo0fKV7cEyoluMnU/edit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Brainstorming Doc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📝 &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1oU_wcxo4RQXvG72szW5H26VmAeJJhytjsw0UcQzV_l8/edit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Draft Paper&lt;/a&gt; - currently in progress, come claim a section!&lt;br&gt;
🙋🏾 &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1NJY-jt2T1MlWYiJ5P1sL8aGscYYzrCuZ1ThXFbdFWKI/edit#gid=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Contributor Tracking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/code-check-club/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Discussions&lt;/a&gt; (replacing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://join.slack.com/t/codereviewguide/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
📖 &lt;a href=&#34;https://code-check-club.github.io/code-review-guide/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Guide&lt;/a&gt; (just in outline form for now)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Simulation Workshops</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/datasim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/datasim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-simulation-for-factorial-designs&#34;&gt;Data simulation for factorial designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will cover the basics of simulation using {faux}. We will simulate data with factorial designs by specifying the within and between-subjects factor structure, each cell mean and standard deviation, and correlations between cells where appropriate. This can be used to create simulated data sets to be used in preparing the analysis code for pre-registrations or registered reports. We will also create data sets for simulation-based power analyses. Students will need to have very basic knowledge of R and R Markdown, and have installed {faux}, {afex} and {tidyverse}.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-simulation-for-mixed-designs&#34;&gt;Data simulation for mixed designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will cover simulating data for a mixed design, where trials are crossed with subjects. We will learn how to analyse this using {lme4}, with a focus on understanding how the simulation parameters correspond to the output. Finally, we will learn how to use simulation to calculate power. Students will need to have basic knowledge of R and R Markdown, some familiarity with mixed designs (even if they don’t currently analyse them with mixed models) and have installed {faux}, {afex}, {tidyverse}, and {lme4}.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ManyFaces</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/manyfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/manyfaces/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Day Chart Challenge</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/30dcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/30dcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first year participating in the 30-day chart challenge. I made a book of tutorials for each chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/30dcc/30DCC_hu4b549ef084c1a92c12085aca1809039e_1213740_f91894936475eb39a2239ee779799c07.png 400w,
               /project/30dcc/30DCC_hu4b549ef084c1a92c12085aca1809039e_1213740_c75aa08b5ba1698f7675e9b57db105e5.png 760w,
               /project/30dcc/30DCC_hu4b549ef084c1a92c12085aca1809039e_1213740_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://debruine.github.io/project/30dcc/30DCC_hu4b549ef084c1a92c12085aca1809039e_1213740_f91894936475eb39a2239ee779799c07.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;428&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/shiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shiny lets you make web applications that do anything you can code in R. For example, you can share your data analysis in a dynamic way with people who don&amp;rsquo;t use R, collect and visualize data, or even make data aRt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is a wealth of material available on the internet to help you get started with Shiny, it can be difficult to see how everything fits together. This class will take a predominantly live coding approach, rather than a lecture-only approach, so you can code along with the instructor and deal with the inevitable bugs and roadblocks together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class will teach you the basics of Shiny app programming, giving you skills that will form the basis of almost any app you want to build. By the end of the class, you will have created a custom app that collects and saves data, allows users to dynamically visualize the data, and produces downloadable reports.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faux</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/faux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/faux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is useful to be able to simulate data with a specified structure. The faux package provides some functions to make this process easier for factorial designs and single- or multilevel data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebMorph</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/webmorph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/webmorph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of WebMorph and the associated R package, webmorphR, is to make the construction of image stimuli more reproducible, with a focus on face stimuli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;info&#34;&gt;
webmorphR is now on CRAN!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This development of these tools was funded by ERC grant #647910 (KINSHIP).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimentum</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/experimentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/experimentum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Experimentum is an open-source, online platform for psychology studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa DeBruine, Rebecca Lai, Benedict Jones, Rifah Abdullah, Gaby Mahrholz. (2020). Experimentum (Version v.0.2). Zenodo. doi:10.5281/zenodo.2634355&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Science Accelerator</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/psa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/psa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The PSA is a globally distributed network of psychological science laboratories that coordinates data collection for democratically selected studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a founding member and was elected to a 3-year term as an Associate Director in 2021. I also was one of the lead researchers on the first project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psyTeachR</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/psyteachr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/psyteachr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The psyTeachR team at the University of Glasgow School of Psychology and Institute of Neuroscience and Psychology has successfully made the transition to teaching reproducible research using R across all undergraduate and postgraduate levels. Our curriculum now emphasizes essential ‘data science’ graduate skills that have been overlooked in traditional approaches to teaching, including programming skills, data visualisation, data wrangling and reproducible reports. Students learn about probability and inference through data simulation as well as by working with real datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
