<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiny | Lisa DeBruine</title>
    <link>https://debruine.github.io/tag/shiny/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://debruine.github.io/tag/shiny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>shiny</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://debruine.github.io/media/icon_hud41de7153c7fa400a999f8d222dc5c78_8091_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>shiny</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/tag/shiny/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Club</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/coding-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/coding-club/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making an R package develops generic coding skills and gives you valuable insight to how R works. We’ll cover setting up a package project, creating functions, documenting them with roxygen, creating vignettes, unit testing, package testing, version control with git, and distribution with github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sessions run Wednesdays from 16:05 to 17:00 UK time from October 5 to December 7, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Register for free at &lt;a href=&#34;https://coding-club-packages.eventbrite.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EventBrite&lt;/a&gt; to help us keep organised and let us know a little bit about your experience. Space is unlimited, so don’t worry if you can’t make all of the dates. We’ll record the sessions and make them public ASAP so you can catch up if you miss the live session.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny</title>
      <link>https://debruine.github.io/project/shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debruine.github.io/project/shiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shiny lets you make web applications that do anything you can code in R. For example, you can share your data analysis in a dynamic way with people who don&amp;rsquo;t use R, collect and visualize data, or even make data aRt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is a wealth of material available on the internet to help you get started with Shiny, it can be difficult to see how everything fits together. This class will take a predominantly live coding approach, rather than a lecture-only approach, so you can code along with the instructor and deal with the inevitable bugs and roadblocks together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class will teach you the basics of Shiny app programming, giving you skills that will form the basis of almost any app you want to build. By the end of the class, you will have created a custom app that collects and saves data, allows users to dynamically visualize the data, and produces downloadable reports.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
